A Guide to the Records of Lieutenant Governor Lawrence Doulgas Wilder, 1975-1990 (bulk 1986-1989)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of Lieutenant Governor Lawrence Doulgas Wilder, 1975-1990 (bulk 1986-1989)
The Library of Virginia
33696, 35539
27.05 cu. ft. (73 boxes)
Lieutenant Governor (1986-1990: Wilder)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 33696 was transferred by the Office of the Lieutenant Governor on 21 December 1989. Accession 35539 was transferred by Gov. Lawrence Douglas Wilder on 31 October 1996.
Biographical Information
Lawrence Douglas Wilder was born in Richmond, Va., on January 17, 1931. He graduated from Virginia Union University in 1951 and afterwards was drafted into the Army, where he served in the Korean War from 1952-1953 and received a bronze star. He then attended the Howard University School of Law and graduated in 1959. Douglas Wilder was elected to the Virginia Senate in 1969 as the first African American member since Reconstruction and served in the Senate for five terms. In 1985, he was elected to the office of Lieutenant Governor as the first African American to be elected to statewide office in Virginia. L. Douglas Wilder won the election for Governor of Virginia in 1989 and served from January 13, 1990 to January 14, 1994. He was the first African American to be elected as Governor in United States.
Scope and Content
Records, 1975-1990 (bulk 1986-1989), including clippings, correspondence, memorandum, notes, reports, schedules, speeches, and subject files of Lieutenant Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder. The records are housed in 73 boxes and arranged into two series, Series I: Correspondence and Subject Files [Accession 35539] and Series II: Correspondence and Subject Files [Accession 33696]. The records were maintained and transferred to the Library separately and the collection was maintained in its original separate order. These records document Lawrence Douglas Wilder's work as Lieutenant Governor from 1986 to 1990.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Correspondence and Subject Files, 1975-1990 (bulk 1986-1989) [Accession 35539]
Series II: Correspondence and Subject Files, 1982-1989 [Accession 33696]
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and Subject Files [Accession 35539], 1975-1990 (bulk 1986-1989)., Extent: 8.15 cu. ft. (19 boxes). (Box 1-19)
  This series consists of correspondence and subject files, 1975-1990 (bulk 1986-1989), of Lieutenant Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder. The series is arranged alphabetically by folder title into nineteen (19) boxes and include agendas, clippings, correspondence, memorandum, notes, reports, schedules, and speeches, among other materials. The collection is further divided into sections: Commission on Transportation in the Twenty-First Century; Correspondence; Governor's Schedule (Gov. Baliles); Speeches; and Subject and reference files.
  In September 1986 Governor Baliles convened a special session of the General Assembly that passed a 12-year, $12 billion transportation package to modernize the state's roads, seaports, airports, and mass transit, partially funded by a half cent increase in the sales tax. The Commission on Transportation in the Twenty-First Century records includes information on the transportation plan and contains several reports and studies.
  The Correspondence is arranged by General or Constituent. The General Correspondence includes information on General Assembly interns and reports on staff used in support of Gubernatorial Commissions. The Constituent Correspondence concerns a variety of topics including abortion, education, health insurance, and transportation. Also included are numerous congratulatory letters for winning the gubernatorial election in 1989.
  Of note are copies of Lieutenant Governor Wilder's speeches, which are arranged chronologically. Also included are copies of Governor Baliles daily schedules.
  The subject and reference files include clippings, correspondence, memorandum, notes, and reports, among other materials. Topics include correspondence with members of the Virginia General Assembly, invitations to attend events, nomination by the editors of Ebony for an American Black Achievement Award, copies of FOCUS magazine, issues regarding a proposed Virginia coal slurry pipeline, Governor's Regulatory Reform Advisory Board, Governors Task Force on Science and Technology, a trip to Israel and the Soviet Union, and juveniles in adult jails. Additional topics include Leadership retreats, industrial revenue bonds, Southern Legislative Conference, domestic violence and spousal abuse, uranium mining, the Urban Enterprise Act of Kemp-Garcia, establishment of a Virginia Weather Center, and funding issues at Whittaker Hospital in Newport News, Virginia.
  - Commission on Transportation in the Twenty-First Century
    - Agenda, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Analysis, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bonded Debt in Virginia, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Commission structure, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Critical Needs Subcommittee, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - Economic Impact Study, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Financial Options Subcommittee, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Financial Options Subcommittee, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Funding formula, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Gas tax, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Harris summary, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Harrison comments, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Highway construction, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Legal issues, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Sen. J. Granger, Proposal, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Mass transit, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - News clippings, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Phase I Report, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Phase II Report, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Ports, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Report, A Solvable Problem: Transportation in Northern Virginia, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
    - Report, Final Report Construction Industry Capacity to Absorb Additional Highway Funding (Document 4), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Report, Legal Advisory Committee to the Governor's Commission (Document 7), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Report, Local Government Advisory Committee to the Commission, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Report, Subcommittee on Critical Needs (Document 5), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Report, Subcommittee on State and Local Relations (draft), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Report, Subcommittee on State and Local Relations (Document 9) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Revenue, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Dept. of Transportation, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
    - Virginia Dept. of Transportation, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence
    - General, Administrative law judge, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - General, Convention material, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - General, General Assembly, 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - General, General Assembly, Interns, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - General, General Assembly, Interns, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - General, General Assembly, Interns, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - General, General Assembly, Interns, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - General, Gubernatorial Commission, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - General, Office of the Governor, Staffing chart, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Constituent, 1986, 1988, 1989 June-August (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Constituent, 1989 October 3-23 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Constituent, 1989 October 24 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Constituent, 1989 October 25-27 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Constituent, 1989 October 30-31 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Constituent, 1989 November 2-15 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Constituent, 1989 November 16-22 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Constituent, 1989 November 22-27 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Constituent, 1989 November 28-December 5 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Governor's Schedule (Gov. Baliles)
    - 1989 January 3-10 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1989 January 11-17 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1989 January 18-25 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1989 January 26-31 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1989 February 1-7 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1989 February 8-9 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 1989 February 10-18 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 1989 February 20-28 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 1989 March 2-21 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 1989 March 22-31 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 1989 April 1-6 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 1989 April 7-15 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 1989 April 17-23 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1989 April 25-30 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1989 May 3-8 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1989 May 10-13 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1989 May 15-22 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1989 May 23-31 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Speeches
    - Martin Luther King Convocation-Virginia Union University, 1986 January 18 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Virginia State University-Martin Luther King Tribute, 1986 January 20 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Lynchburg NAACP Freedom Fund Banquet, 1986 February 16 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Urban League Equal Opportunity Dinner (Baltimore, Maryland), 1986 February 27 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - NAACP Regional Director's, 1986 March 14 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Harvard Black Law Students Association, 1986 March 15 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Washington Association of Black Journalist, 1986 March 19 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Hampton University-Black Family Conference, 1986 March 21 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - National Bar Association, 1986 March 22 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Opportunities Industrialization Center, 1986 April 4 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Arkansas Black Democratic Caucus, 1986 April 12 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Greensboro NAACP Freedom Fund Banquet, 1986 April 16 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Richmond Metro U.S. Savings Bond Kickoff 1986, 1986 April 17 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Montgomery County NAACP Freedom Fund Banquet, 1986 April 20 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Regional Conference of Civil Rights (Virginia Beach, Virginia), 1986 April 26 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Tidewater Are Business and Contractors Association, 1986 April 24 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - National Forum for Black Public Administrators, 1986 April 30 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Kennedy's-King Dinner, 1986 May 1 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - San Antonio Black Lawyers Association, 1986 May 2 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - International Personnel Management Association, 1986 May 5 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - NAACP Legal Defense Fund, 1986 May 6 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Howard University Law School Commencement, 1986 May 10 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Ferrum College Commencement, 1986 May 11 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Chamber of Commerce-Industrial Development Committee Meeting, 1986 May 13 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Commencement University of Virginia, 1986 May 18 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Virginia World Trade Luncheon, 1986 May 21 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Southern Prince George's COBA (Oxonhill, Maryland), 1986 May 23 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Bisco Dinner, 1986 May 29 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Black Law Students Association University of Baltimore, 1986 May 31 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Tulsa Urban League, 1986 June 7 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Virginia Admissions Council on Black Concerns, 1986 June 9 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Jefferson-Huguenot-Wythe High School, 1986 June 10 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Commencement Armstrong-Kennedy High School, 1986 June 12 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Virginia Western Community College, 1986 June 13 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Texas Coalition of Black Democrats, 1986 June 27 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Baltimore National Convention NAACP, 1986 July 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - North Carolina Democratic Convention, 1986 July 12 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Downtown Portsmouth Association, 1986 July 15 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Omega Psi Psi Fraternity Inc., 75th Anniversary Grand Conclave, 1986 July 29 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Sheriff's Association Conference, 1986 August 4 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Sigma Pi Phi Youth Achievement Lunch, 1986 August 12 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Fraternal Order of Police, 1986 August 15 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Stafford County NAACP, 1986 September 13 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - STOP Inc., 1986 September 19 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Richmond Bar Association, 1986 September 25 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Dulles Area Board of Trade, 1986 September 30 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - City of Franklin Fall Festival Association, 1986 October 2 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - The Richmond Forum Club Sorvan Center, 1986 October 7 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Keith, Damon, J., Civic and Humanitarian Award Reception, 1986 October 26 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Surry County, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Family Services of Charlottesville, 1986 October 30 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Third Annual VABEO Conference, 1986 October 31 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - NAACP Life Membership Dinner, 1986 November 2 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Mobile Community Organization, 1986 November 8 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner, 1986 November 11 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Essex County Urban League, 1986 November 12 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Community College Associates, 1986 November 14 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Hampton Road Chamber of Commerce, 1986 November 16 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - 87th Eastern Armed Robbery Conference, 1986 November 20 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - National Alliance of Black School Educators, 1986 November 22 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The Emporia Rotary Club, 1986 November 25 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1986 December 9 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Commencement-Cheyney University of Pennsylvania, 1986 December 14 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Petersburg Bar Association, 1986 December 16 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Community Action Agencies Conference, 1987 January 23 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Howard University Charter Day, 1987 February 27 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Elizabeth City State University Founder's Day, 1987 March 3 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Crewe Kiwanis Inter-Club Meeting, 1987 April 14 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Pittsburgh Branch NAACP Human Rights Dinner, 1987 May 8 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - North Carolina Central University Commencement Exercise, 1987 May 9 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Association of School Business Officials, 1987 May 13 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Clinch Valley College Commencement Exercise, 1987 May 17 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Blue Ridge Community College Commencement Exercise, 1987 May 24 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Commencement Mount Vernon High School, 1987 June 11 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Windsor High School Commencement Exercises, 1987 June 16 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - International Longshoremen's Association Convention, 1987 July 14 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Taft Seminar for Teachers Banquet, 1987 July 29 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Silver-haired Legislature, 1987 August 4 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Downtown Richmond Kiwanis Club John Marshall Hotel, 1987 August 10 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Petersburg Public School Convocation, 1987 August 31 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - The Governor's Conference on Employment and Training, 1987 September 22 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Remarks Made to the Virginia Municipal League, 1987 September 28 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - The Council of State Chambers of Commerce, 1987 September 30 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Carroll County Democratic Party Dinner, 1987 October 3 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Portsmouth/Chesapeake Board of Realtors Luncheon, 1987 October 19 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Virginia State's Farm and Ownership Day, 1987 October 21 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Charlottesville-Albemarle Bar Association, 1987 November 11 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Franklin County Education Association's Fourth Annual Partner's in Education Dinner, 1987 November 17 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - 107th Annual Membership Dinner of the Petersburg Chamber of Commerce Fort Lee Officer's Club, 1987 December 2 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - The Virginia Law and Government Project, 1987 December 9 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - The William Byrd Community House, 1988 January 20 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Senate Finance Committee Public Hearing on SB 112, 1988 January 26 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - The Virginia Health Care Associations Winter Legislative Conference, 1988 February 17 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Blacksburg Chamber of Commerce Annual Award Dinner, 1988 March 24 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Virginia Tech Speaker's Forum, 1988 April 19 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Kiwanis Club of Roanoke, 1988 May 4 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - AFL-CIO Community Services Activities Union Counselor Graduation Banquet, 1988 May 11 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Southeastern Tidewater Regional Coordination Workshop, 1988 May 12 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Miller and Rhodes Academic Achievers' Luncheon, Miller and Rhodes Tea Room, 1988 May 13 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Commencement Christopher Newport College, 1988 May 15 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Brunswick Senior High School Annual Academic Awards Banquet, 1988 May 18 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - National Transportation Week Luncheon Norfolk Yacht and Country Club, 1988 May 19 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners, AFL-CIO Eleventh constitutional Convention, 1988 May 19 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Student National Medical Associations MCV Graduates Banquet, 1988 May 21 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Central Virginia Chapter Air Pollution Control Association, 1988 May 26 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Commencement Appomattox County High School, 1988 June 10 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Commencement Nottoway Correctional Center, 1988 June 15 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Greater Washington Financial Institutions Association, 1988 June 16 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Commencement at Stonewall Jackson High School, 1988 June 17 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Carver Road Ruritan Club, 1988 June 18 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Commencement Danville Community College, 1988 July 29 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - National Apostolate of Maronites of Convention, 1988 July 30 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Miller and Schroeder Forum Luncheon, 1988 August 1 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - The Virginia State Air Force Association, 1988 August 13 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Welcoming COMDEF '88 International Defense Exhibit and Symposia, 1988 September 14 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Fairfax Chamber of Commerce, 1988 September 15 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Hampton University Convocation, 1988 September 18 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Greater Springfield Chamber of Commerce, 1988 September 21 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Tidewater Chapter of the Virginia Credit Union League, 1988 September 23 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Wise County Democratic Committee, 1988 October 1 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Norfolk-Portsmouth Bar Association, 1988 October 20 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - 5th District Jefferson-Jackson Dinner, 1988 October 21 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Loudoun County Democratic Committee, 1988 October 24 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Prince William Chamber of Commerce, 1988 October 27 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Annadale Chamber of Commerce (Fairfax Virginia), 1988 November 10 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - R.E. B. Awards for Teaching Excellence, 1988 November 14 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Wayne State University Millender Lectureship Program, 1988 November 17 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Loudoun County Chamber of Commerce (Sterling Virginia), 1988 November 19 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Expanding Horizons Program, Charles City High School, 1988 November 22 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Goochland County Democrats, 1988 November 30 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Alexandria Democratic Business Forum, 1988 December 1 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - The Voter Registrars of Virginia, 1988 December 1 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Subject and reference files
    - ABA nomination, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Abortion, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Black and White in Richmond, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Coal dust, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Coal slurry issues, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - Comparative politics, 1977-1981 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Constitutional officers, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Senators, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Senators, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Senators, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Senators, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with U.S. Senators, 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Cramwell, Richard C., Delegate, 1981-1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Crouch, Paul P., Jr., 1988 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Crusade for Voters, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - CSX Corp., 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Daniels and Bell Inc., 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Darden, Colgate, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Davis, Richard T., 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Day, Barnie K., 1986 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Dozoretz, Dr. Ronald I., 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Drawings, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Eastern Virginia Medical School, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Ebony, 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Equal Rights Amendment Ratification Council, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Federalism, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - FOCUS, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - FOCUS, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - FOCUS, 1988 January-August (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - FOCUS, 1989 October (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Fogarty, Andrew B., 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Fraternal Order of Police, 1986-1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Fraternal Order of Police, Virginia State Lodge, 1986-1989 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Gephardt, Richard A., 1987 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Goldman, Paul, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Goode, Virgil H., Keynote address, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Governor's Commission on Block Grants, Draft report, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Governor's Regulatory Review, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Governor's Science and Technology Project, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Gray, Dr. Clarence C., III, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Gray, Earl H., 1986-1988 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Guardsmen Inc., 1986-1988 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Hampton, George, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Harris, Kelly, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Hart, Gary, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Hartke, Vance, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Honda, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Honorariums, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Hough, Phillip G., 1988 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - House Appropriations Committee, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - HB 780, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Housing and Urban Development, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Houston, Sam, 1975-1987 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Houston, Sam, 1975-1987 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Inaugural dinner, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Industrial Development Bonds, National reform, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Israel-Soviet Union, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - Jackson, Rev. Jesse, 1987-1989 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - JLARC, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Judges, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Judicial appointments, 1986-1988 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Juveniles in adult jails, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Kennedy, Edward M., Senator, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1986-1988 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Lambert, Benjamin J., III, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Language in the Senate, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Latham, Weldon H., 1989 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Leadership Retreat II (Miami, Fla.), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Leadership Retreat IV (Paradise Island, Bahamas), 1987 June (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
    - Leadership Retreat V (Nassau, Bahamas), 1987 December (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Leadership Retreat VII (Miami, Fla.), 1988 December (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Leftwich, Maxine, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Leggett, Ike, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Licht, Richard A., 1987 (Box 17, Folder 9)